[music]
>> Hello and welcome to the drop shipment
session. You can think that the drop
shipment is a very popular term in the
e-commerce scenarios where you sell
something to customers which is not in
your warehouse. Maybe you even do not
have warehouse. You do not store the
good. Why? Because they are in your
vendor warehouse or maybe they will be
produced and vendor will be sending them
directly to your customer and then you
will handle the invoicing.
Business Central support this scenario
like for a long long long time, but with
this release
we allow you extra level of
capabilities. For example, you can have
now more options
on how you create purchase documents for
your drop shipment sales documents. You
also more relaxed in the way how you
perform the operations in the relation
to the sequence of the operations and it
also become more forget forgettable
forgiving forgiving in the relation of
mistakes. What if you make something
wrong? You can now fix your error
easier. But let's go into the details.
Old the version of the Business Central
instruct you
to use following sequence of operations.
First you post receipt or shipment
doesn't matter they actually
posted together automatically they
binded doesn't matter where you start
from, but then you must to post sales
invoice
and send it to customer. Only then you
are allowed to process purchase invoice
from your vendor either by
updating purchase order or using get
receipt lines.
A bit restrictive I would say. Why you
cannot process document which you
receive from the vendor immediately?
Very good question.
In the version which we are releasing in
the 2026 wave one
we added
more flexibility.
So now most scenarios are unlocked.
Again, you starting the same way you
post receipt maybe shipment like
together doesn't matter, but then you
can decide if you want to post sales or
invoice first or you want to post sales
purchase invoice first either directly
in the purchase order or indirectly via
get receipt lines.
Interesting part you can also
when you processing purchase order you
can post it as receipt and invoice
immediately and
shipment will be also updated.
And a couple of more scenarios uh
added because we also have a
functionality which is called order get
order lines.
You can use get order lines as a more
elaborate replacement for get
get receipt lines. For example, if you
have invoice connected to multiple
uh
orders or receipts
or another one if you activated receipt
on invoice
in your purchase document created from
the drop shipment you can post receipt
and invoice directly
uh of order via get receipt lines get
order lines and then
post invoice and send it to your
customers.
But
we'll definitely need to look at all of
them, but before couple of more slides
then we can do the one demo.
Purchase order creation.
Original scenarios you can create uh
purchase documents either using
requisition worksheet where we have a
get sales order action under drop
shipment group and then you can get all
outstanding purchase documents
or one by one
in from the purchase order directly. You
start by creating purchase order and
then you get sales orders.
In this version in this release
we have extra options for you.
So now you can do it from the sales
order page, from order planning page or
from the planning worksheet.
Now to the demo.
I prepared the sales document for you
which includes number of lines. All of
them are marked as a drop shipment. But
before we do anything in this document,
let me jump to the
order planning
page
and show you that uh
we can calculate it for sales demand
and you can see the lines here.
So now drop shipment lines are respected
by order planning.
Planning worksheet also has a new group
called drop shipment where you can
select get order lines to do to get
actually the same. It's very similar to
what we see in the requisition worksheet
today. Oh and by the way, not use the
request approval action.
But we do it differently this time. We
return back to the sales document and we
do it differently. We go to actions
functions create purchase document
create purchase order.
And here you are. We system calculated
which lines to be ordered and you can
see the indicator that all of them are
related to drop shipment.
All of them are from different vendors
which is not the really common scenarios
in the in the
e-commerce, but now all three where
purchase documents are created let's
experiment with all of them and try
slightly different things. Let's open
the first one.
Populate the vendor invoice number and
just hit post. Receipt and invoice all
together.
Purchase order has disappeared it
posted. Remember the sales invoice is
sales order is still only shipped and it
was shipped by by posting this document.
Do you want to explore purchase
document? Not right now.
What about two others?
We will do a different versions
with them as well. So here
we will scroll down. We do nothing. We
only create this document then we
scroll down
to invoice details and activate the new
toggle receipt on invoice. You might
learn more about this one in the order
uh matching video.
And then we create
purchase invoice.
New purchase invoice
for
our vendor.
Let's populate the vendor invoice number
and use
line functions new get order lines.
I have so many, but I'm more interested
in this last ones. They are my drop
shipment related.
And if I will open related information
matched order lines
you can see there is order, but no
shipment.
Okay? Can I post it?
Yes, I can.
The invoice was posted, but if you will
go back to the purchase order we will
see something.
Where is our purchase?
Let's return to our purchase order this
one
and we can scroll to the
to the right
and we can see our quantity
received and invoiced.
I didn't do anything with this purchase
document. It was processed
automatically. So together with a
payable agents and automation that
sounds as a interesting scenario.
The last one the last one
to experiment
let's just post it
as receipt the very
classical scenario.
And now it's time to return to the sales
to the sales order.
So sales order all of these items which
we know are sourced by three different
vendors all of them are
shipped. Nothing is invoiced. So that's
back to our
enhancement about the order of
operations. So you can do the purchase
part independently of the sales part. So
depends on your company process you can
do it differently.
But now
let's navigate to the to the shipments.
Find the last one
because it's the only one which is not
invoiced on purchase side and we use the
undo shipment to cancel the the
transaction.
And now the item is completely returned
to the vendor and ready for the
additional process.
Let's go back.
Find the purchase document.
Update vendor invoice number.
Check that I selected the right one
quantity to received and posted again
receive an invoice.
Nice and smooth.
Again with the sequence of operations
errors and planning parameters
and and the different approach to create
documents.
With this short collection of demos you
can see the new enhancements in the
uh drop shipment functional which allows
you to
vary different sequence of operations
benefit from different method of
creation of purchase documents and of
course,
use a
very convenient undo shipment
functionality in the drop shipment
scenarios as well.
Thank you for watching, and let's stay
connected. You can find additional
videos in the description, plus you can
always reach out to us via LinkedIn or
via Engage.